Michael Hunt

Physics PhD and aspiring data scientist

mbh038@gmail.com | ○ mbh038 | ➤ Michael Hunt

Currently

I have worked as a lecturer in the HE in FE sector for 19 years, having previously been a research physicist in Switzerland and France for 6 years. I have written, managed and delivered a number of HE courses up to Masters level, including a BSc Renewable Energy and Carbon Management. In the last two years I have successfully completed many (>25) MOOCs in statistical analysis, machine learning, big data and more, mainly using R, and Python but also Matlab, MS Azure and other tools. I have so far used these new skills to carry out market research, to model heat flows in old buildings, to simulate wind speed and solar variation and to model a pumped storage energy solution for a local town. The heat flow work was part of a long running collaboration with conservation officers within Cornwall Council, funded by a Townscape Heritage Initiative lottery money. It was published last year and presented at an international conference (EECHB 2016). I am now embarking on a machine learning/IoT project to develop a biologger and software to determine the state of movement of farm animals from accelerometer data alone.

Employment

investigations.

1998-	Cornwall College HE lecturer, course manager and curriculum area manager.
1997-1998	CNRS Lab. Louis Neel OXSEN Research Fellow, developing magnetic transistors.
1996–1997	Physics Department, University of Zuerich Oxygen isotope investigations of Hi Tc superconductors using
	dilatometry.
1995–1996	ABB Applied Physics Group, Corporate Research Centre, Baden Daettwil Dilatometric studies of 1 MW Hi Tc
	superconducting current limiter.
1995–1996	Solid State Physics Lab., ETH Zuerich Low temperature studies of transport properties in metals
1981–1982	Research Centre, British Gas, Solihull, UK Coding in FORTRAN and assembly to support gas dispersion

Education

1989–1992	University of Bristol PhD Physics "A de Haas-van Alphen Investigation of the heavy fermion superconductor Ce
	CU_2Si_2" (supervisor: Mike Springford)
1987-1988	University of Sussex MSc Physics by Research (Distinction)
1982-1985	University of Cambridge BA Natural Science (Physics)

Presentations

Talks 2016 EECHB: Life Cycle Analysis of Historic Buildings in Cornwall(EECHB, Brussels, Belgium)

Publications

I have 24 publications in peer reviewed journals, almost all dating from my years as a post-grad and post-doc 1989-1998. See my profiles on Research Gate or Google Scholar for listing of these. One was published in Nature and has over 300 citations. More recently (2016) I presented work at an international conference (EECHB, 2016) on energy efficiency in old buildings. This was an analysis carried out using R of heat flow through thick, solid walls.

Certifications

Many online courses in 2015-2016. The code written for most of these can be found in repos on my GitHub page Most courses required between 20 and 100 hours of work over 4 - 8 weeks

100%

U.

page.	Most courses required between 20 and 100 hours of work over 4 - 8 weeks.		
Coursera	The Data Scientist's Toolbox	JHU	100%
Coursera	R Programming	JHU	100%
Coursera	Getting and Cleaning Data	JHU	100%
Coursera	Exploratory Data Analysis	JHU	100%
Coursera	Reproducible Research	JHU	100%
Coursera	Statistical Inference	JHU	100%
Coursera	Regression Models	JHU	100%
Coursera	Practical Machine Learning	JHU	100%
Coursera	Developing Data Products	JHU	100%
Coursera	Data Analysis and Statistical Inference	Duke	99%
edX	The Analytics Edge	MITx	96%
FutureLear	nBig Data	U. Warwic	k100%
Coursera	Introduction to Big Data	U. San	100%
		Diego	
Coursera	Hadoop Platform and Application Framework	U. San	100%
		Diego	
Coursera	Introduction to Big Data Analytics	U. San	100%
		Diego	
Coursera	Programming for Everybody	U.	100%
		Michigan	

Using Python to Access Web Data

Coursera

		Michigan	
Coursera	Using Databases with Python	U.	100%
		Michigan	
edX	Introduction to Computer Science and Programming using Python	MITx	98%
edX	Introduction to Computational Thinking and Data Science	MITx	97%
edX	Data Science and ML Essentials	Microsoft	93%
Lagonita	Statistical Learning	U.	88%
		Stanford	
edX	Machine Learning	U.	100%
		Stanford	
edX	Statistics and R	HarvardX	100%
edX	Introduction to Linear Models and Matrix Algebra	HarvardX	100%
edX	Statistical Inference and Modeling for High-throughput Experiments	HarvardX	98%
edX	High-Dimensional Data Analysis	HarvardX	100%
edX	Introduction to Bioconductor: Annotation and Analysis of Genomes and	HarvardX	99%
	Genomic Assays		
edX	High-performance Computing for Reproducible Genomics	HarvardX	99%
edX	Case Studies in Functional Genomics	HarvardX	99%
edX	Global Warming Science	HarvardX	100%
edX	Case Studies in Functional Genomics	MITx	100%
FutureLearnCauses of Climate Change U. Bergen 100			
Coursera	Introduction to programming with Matlab	Vanderbilt	100%
		U.	

Technical skills

Python

R

C++

MATLAB

Statistics

LaTeX

Git

Linux

Machine learning

Bash

Data visualisation

Awards	
Placements	
Interests	
	Trail running - several times a week, most weeks. Project Euler - 181 problems solved so far, using Python, C++, Mathematica, Matlab and R. Homing in on the UK top 50
Links	
	≥ email

References

Projects

Available on request.

Research gate 8 Google scholar

○ github **y** twitter